<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics | KidQuant</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/category/economics/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/category/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Economics</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:4321/media/icon_huf195f9a67bfe19c82d5f0ba6a67922fa_2030_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Economics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/category/economics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York State of Decline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how New York became America&amp;rsquo;s financial center? It&amp;rsquo;s not like the New York Stock Exchange is the only securities market in the country. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s the NASDAQ (another in New York), but there is one in Miami, Chicago, and Philidelphia. In fact, Philadelphia initially obtained financial supremacy in the country with the establishment of the Bank of Pennsylvania in 1780.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I learned during my Finance undergraduate studies, it all amounts to pure luck why Philadephia isn&amp;rsquo;t America&amp;rsquo;s financial center. The main reason why economic supremacy shifted from Philly was NYC&amp;rsquo;s geographical advantage with the Erie Canal construction. The Erie Canal connected to the Hudson River to the Great Lakes and the fastest-growing places in the Appalachian Mountains. The canal helped solidify New York&amp;rsquo;s position as America&amp;rsquo;s center for commercial trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point of this history lesson: nothing lasts forever. If a country, region, state, or area loses its comparative advantage, it may also lose its overall economic advantage. Enter James Altucher, author of the &lt;em&gt;NYC is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/em&gt; article [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. He wrote a scathing rebuke of the current situation involving New York City, arguing, although the city has been through a lot, this time is different. James obviously addressed all of the crucial points, which are undeniably true. Why else would high profile individuals such as Jerry Seinfield, Mark Cuban, and Bill De&amp;rsquo;Blasio respond to an article on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say whether I agree with the points raised in the article; there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot that I can add to strengthen the &amp;ldquo;New York is Dead&amp;rdquo; argument. We can debate what it would mean for an entire city to be &amp;ldquo;dead,&amp;rdquo; whether it&amp;rsquo;s fewer people choosing to travel to NYC or high-net-worth individuals and established industries choosing to relocate to other areas. What I can say is that the threats to New York&amp;rsquo;s financial position are &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, James outlines that many people in March/April relocated when the Pandemic situation in NYC worsened; the second wave of people left when crime was spiraling out of control. Some may suggest that the stores of New Yorkers fleeing the city in droves may be greatly exaggerated [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that the COVID pandemic merely exacerbated what many New Yorkers have been feeling all along: &amp;ldquo;I gotta get out of here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows anything about living in New York understands how unfeasible it is to maintain a decent standard of living unless you&amp;rsquo;re very poor or wealthy [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_pop_change.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Population Change&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following map shows the population change of New York counties within the last 9 years. The plot measures cumulative growth since April 2010; each county is shaded in a different color. The closer the shade is to blue, the larger the population growth within the last 9 years (and vice versa). As we can see, change in the NY population has been on a steady decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the five boroughs, except Richmond County (Staten Island), are the only counties with experienced population growth within the same period, albeit very modest. Regardless, Census Bureau data suggest that NYC has been bleeding residents as early as 2016 [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t clear whether COVID and crime are the final straw for many life-long New Yorkers. Instead, the current situation has allowed people to imagine the possibility of becoming life-long somewhere-elsers. As James pointed out, people are willing to tolerate the higher taxes and cost of living because of business/employment opportunities and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_ue_rate.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Unemployment Rate&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is a plot of the same region, except this measures the August Unemployment by county. The vast majority of areas in New York have an unemployment rate similar to the national average of 8.4 percent. In stark contrast, the five boroughs (and the surrounding areas) have unemployment rates significantly above the national average, ranging from 12 percent to as high as 20 percent. This unemployment level is consistent with the severe COVID restrictions still imposed on many industries in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, NYC and New York as a whole have not experienced a second wave in the same way other cities across the globe have. Governor Cuomo once suggested that people were &amp;ldquo;fleeing other states because it&amp;rsquo;s a safe state.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] While there is nothing to indicate that people have weighed the opportunity cost of looking for work as opposed to catching COVID,. Instead, people have decided that it&amp;rsquo;s too expensive to live in NYC for all of the city&amp;rsquo;s headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be realistic; changes in mortgage rates and what people are looking for in a home provide an incentive for people who were already considering moving. The largest incentive for people living in the city (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter which city) is the cost [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. In addition, ~80 percent of NYC employees live in the five boroughs; with NYC-based firms offering more flexible work-from-home policies, that number is likely to decline [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]. Lastly, the COVID Pandemic prevents NYC residents from fully enjoying local amenities, which lowers the incentive to live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if there is no incentive to live here, there is also no incentive to conduct business here. Manhattan Borough President Gale Brewer counted 335 street-level vacancies along Broadway (a ~80 increase from three years ago), a major shopping area/tourist attraction in NYC [&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;]. Other industries are just as amenable to the effects of the pandemic as well. Still, the one affected industry that has the power to effectively reshape NYC is, of course, the &lt;strong&gt;Financial sector&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, New Yorkers (at least, NYC-based finance employees) debated where the next financial hotspot would be, and for a long time, that hotspot appeared to be Hudson Yards. Today, as work-from-home policies have reduced the need for employees in office environments, financial firms are considering reducing its physical presence by at least 20%, according to a study released by the Partnership for New York City [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same study has also pointed out that 1 in four office employers intend to reduce their footprint by at least a fifth, and about 16 percent expect to move jobs out of the city. Companies also expect only 10 percent of their employees to return to the office by the end of summer and just 40 percent by the year-end. The lack of mobility is expected to shrink economic activity by 13 percent this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a personal anecdote, I was expected to return back to the office in mid-September; however, my firm has left work-from-home optional for many employees. From what I here, the office is mostly empty, which should surprise no one. As long as resturants and businesses remain closed, as long as the number of businesses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nyc-dead-forever-heres-why-james-altucher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James Altucher | NYC Is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://nypost.com/2020/08/11/new-yorkers-flee-nyc-in-droves/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Post | New Yorkers Keep Moving To The Suburbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://money.cnn.com/calculator/pf/cost-of-living/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNBC Money | Cost of Living City Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/fredgraph.png?g=w7H1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FRED | Resident Population in NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thehill/status/1285337437867212802?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1285337437867212802%7Ctwgr%5Eshare_0&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fdw-site-staging.dailywire.com%2Fnews%2Fandrew-cuomo-claims-people-are-now-fleeing-to-new-york-because-its-safe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hill | New York State Governor Andrew Cuomo Press Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redfin.com/blog/wfh-leaving-new-york-san-francisco/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RedFin | Post-Pandemic Migration from Expensive Cities Likely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/planning/download/pdf/planning-level/housing-economy/nyc-ins-and-out-of-commuting.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NYC Planning Department | The Ins and Outs of NYC Commuting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/business-vacancies-rise-on-new-york-citys-broadway-11599652800#:~:text=Coronavirus%20pandemic%20strains%20companies%20along,street-level%20vacancies%20along%20Broadway.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal | Business Vacanies Rise on New York City&amp;rsquo;s Broadway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://pfnyc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/actionandcollaboration.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Partnership for New York City | A Call for Action and Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID Vs. Economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-08-22-covid-vs-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-08-22-covid-vs-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about the Mathematics of Pandemics. I&amp;rsquo;ve even talked about the Politics of Pandemics. I&amp;rsquo;m long overdue to discuss the &amp;ldquo;Economics of Pandemics;&amp;rdquo; however, theorizing the potential effects of an inadequate response was pretty pointless, as anyone who has lived through the Great Recession would tell you. After all, &amp;ldquo;ignorance on fire is sometimes better than knowledge on ice,&amp;rdquo; as the saying goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether or not our economic response to COVID was sufficient, the discussion was always framed in a false dichotomy: protecting the vulnerable versus protecting the economy. If one is a pragmatic, normal-thinking individual, these two are not necessarily mutually exclusive. As early as March 27th, the IGM Chicago Forum surveyed more than 40 professional economists regarding the economic lockdowns in response to the COVID-19 crisis. The vast majority of respondents agree (88%) believe that a comprehensive policy response would involve tolerating a massive contraction in economic activity until the spread has dropped significantly (Question A) [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the United States, along with other nations around the world, instituted their lockdowns policy. We initiated our 15 Days to Slow The Spread, which quickly became 30 Days to Slow The Spread. Although most states have very minor COVID restrictions (staying six feet apart, no gatherings greater than 20 people, etc.), other places that were more severely affected are imposing more strict regulations. [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] It just so happens that the places with the strictest COVID regulation are also home to the largest economies in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although most states have partially reopened (except for California), the U.S. economy contracted by a whopping -32.9% in the second quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that sounds like a big number, that&amp;rsquo;s because it is a big number. The Bureau of Economic Analysis calculates GDP on an annualized basis; this facilitates comparison of growth rates over various periods. In other words, the -32.9% figure is what we would get if the economy sustained its growth (or, in this case, decline) for one year. When used to measure very short-term changes (such as locking down for one or two months), it can be misleading. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s probably better to use Year-over-year change, which would record a -9.5% decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-invisible-threat-ever-lurking&#34;&gt;An Invisible Threat Ever Lurking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how economic growth is measured, the catch-22 is unavoidable. COVID is so bad, it warrants locking down the economy to control its spread, but the economy is bad because we are locked down to prevent the spread of COVID. What a paradox&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the risk of infection is very real; we can&amp;rsquo;t expect things to go back to &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; if the risk of transmission is still high. Some would point out that the economic contraction was only severe &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; we failed to control the spread of COVID. The only problem with this theory is that the United States had the slowest contraction out of all the nations which successfully controlled the spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/us_gdp_global.png&#34; alt=&#34;US vs Global GDP&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The virus ravaged Italy and Spain, and they have instituted strict lockdowns in return. Other places in Europe, which did not want to become the next Italy, instituted strict lockdowns. (Canada is included, for no other reason than it is our neighbor to the north) Some may argue that these nations made a significant trade-off; they chose to protect lives over the economy, and now the economy will be better off in the long-run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except now all of these places are relaxing their COVID restrictions and the virus is starting to spread again. Cases are starting to spike in France, while infections are slowly increasing in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/france_spain_covid.png&#34; alt=&#34;France and Spain&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following places are experiencing an uptick in COVID-19 cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spain, Italy, United Kingdom, Belgium, Neterlands, Switzerland, Greece, Portugal, Denmark, Norway, Japan, Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do all of these places have in common? These regions were assumed to be in control of the virus [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]. Now the virus is out of control and these regions are either experiencing a large surge (Japan), or a steady increase in cases (United Kingdom). Whether by pure luck or by a fortunate circumstance, the United States experienced a phenomenon in early June that Europe should have learned in early July: &lt;strong&gt;you can&amp;rsquo;t hide from the virus forever&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the lockdowns aren&amp;rsquo;t supposed to last forever; they just need to be maintained until a vaccine is found [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. There&amp;rsquo;s no mention of when we can expect a COVID-19 anti-viral vaccine to be developed; &amp;ldquo;never&amp;rdquo; is a very realistic timeline for an effective vaccine (the flu vaccine has a 40-70% effectiveness). Regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s apparent that lockdown is not a sustainable strategy. For two reasons: 1) the obvious economic ramifications of keeping the economy locked down and 2) locking down just delays the inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, we don&amp;rsquo;t have guidelines on what it means to reopen safely, or knowledge if this is even possible because the world has never been locked down before. Lockdown is a new concept that has never been tested for efficacy or implementation. Once the virus transmission restarts, the vulnerable and susceptible are still part of the population and will simply die later rather than sooner unless effective measures are taken to protect them. The only thing that can stop transmission of the virus long term is immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, locking down doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent an outbreak; it merely delays or pushes it out over a longer time frame depending on how severe the lockdowns were implemented. One may point out how South Korea infamously flattened the curve and controlled the spread of the virus. What really happened was that the region has been playing consistent whack-a-mole with outbreaks and on-off lockdowns. Despite implementing measures that would not be legal in the United States, the country is now experiencing a surge in cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/south_korea_cases.png&#34; alt=&#34;South Korea&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about New Zealand? Haven&amp;rsquo;t they eradicated the virus? They&amp;rsquo;ve managed to survive 100 days without a single COVID-19 transmission. Sure, New Zealand is a small island with a population of 5 million and a single major airport. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult to suppress transmissions in the long-run; however, the virus eventually resurged without a single transmission from outside the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now confirmed cases have gone from an average of one per day to an average of 10 per day; Auckland is now back in lockdown; and their Prime Minister has delayed their national election [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/new_zealand_cases.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a novel virus, which means that unless there is a vaccine, everyone will be exposed to it eventually. Keeping people locked inside doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the disease; it only delays it. Unfortunately, keeping people locked inside until the spread slows down, or until vaccine, is a very popular solution to a very unsustainable problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eventually-swedens-strategy-will-by-everyones-strategy&#34;&gt;Eventually Sweden&amp;rsquo;s Strategy Will By Everyone&amp;rsquo;s Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve barely mentioned Sweden in this post. As much of the Western world was shutting down large portions of the economy and limiting the mobility of its citizens throughout March, Sweden opted for a much lighter touch. They&amp;rsquo;ve refused to close down service industries, schools are largely left open, and its borders remained open to the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirmed cases spiked as high as 2,530 in a single day (1,247 per day on average); Sweden reached this milestone in early July. At the same time, fatalities have reached as high as 185, 107 per day on average, a milestone in early May. Both metrics have been on a downward trend since, on some recent days, the country has recorded as few as 3 COVID fatalities. The region is also currently averaging 253 new cases per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/sweden_cases_deaths.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockdowns and closed boarders lack a historical, scientific basis from the Swedish perspective. COVID-19 is in every European country, and so far, none of them have been able to slow down the spread considerably. Regardless, journalists and political analysts have considered Sweden a &amp;ldquo;cautionary tale&amp;rdquo; for the world [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;]. They justify this claim by correctly pointing out that Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population-adjusted death rate is significantly higher compared to its Scandinavian neighbors Finland, Denmark, and Norway [&lt;a href=&#34;#10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Sweden ran into similar problems as many other places had in their attempts to control the virus through the least vulnerable population: failing to protect the elderly. According to most research, upwards of 70% of the COVID death toll in Sweden has been people in elderly care services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the same token, people 65 and older comprise 80% of all COVID deaths in the United States. U.S. Governors such as Andrew Cuomo have been heavily criticized by having the highest nursing home death toll in the U.S., despite instituted one of the strongest and most restrictive lockdowns in the country. Despite reaching Phrase Four of its reopening plan, much of the New York economy is still under lockdown; NYC&amp;rsquo;s mayor Bill DeBlasio is still enforcing strict social distancing requirements (except for protest, apparently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/sweden_outperforms.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of Sweden&amp;rsquo;s strategy, at least from Sweden&amp;rsquo;s perspective, is that places that have locked down significantly lower immunity levels than Sweden&amp;rsquo;s. As such, these places may need to lock down again if and when the disease returns (it has already returned). Many experts have claimed that COVID-19, like some other respiratory diseases, will only be subject to the effects of herd immunity when anywhere from 60-80% of the population recovers from it. No one knows what level of serology represents what is known as Heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (NIT), but we do know that antibody studies are undercounting the population&amp;rsquo;s immunity [&lt;a href=&#34;#11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#12&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden&amp;rsquo;s steady decline in deaths and cases may present an advantage very few countries have obtained. Other hands that have managed to clamp down on infections are seeing a daily increase in cases. This suggests that other places around the world may have populations that may be more susceptible to the virus than Sweden. As such, Sweden&amp;rsquo;s economy may be better off in the long run without the on-and-off lockdowns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at Sweden, it may come across as insane that they&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take this approach. However, their approach was the basic science and standard pandemic response prior to 2020 [&lt;a href=&#34;#13&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;]. With that being said, are &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; the insane ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, fall is just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igmchicago.org/surveys/policy-for-the-covid-19-crisis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IGM Forum | Policy for the COVID-19 Crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/national/states-reopening-coronavirus-map/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Washington Post | Where states reopened and cases spiked after U.S. shutdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-europe-slowed-its-coronavirus-cases-from-a-torrent-to-a-trickle-11595240731&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal | How Europe Kept Coronavirus Cases Low Even After Reopening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/08/lockdowns-cant-end-until-covid-19-vaccine-found-study-says&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Guardian | Study: Lockdowns can&amp;rsquo;t end until COVID-19 vaccine is found&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-newzealand/new-cases-end-new-zealands-covid-free-status-auckland-back-in-lockdown-idUSKCN257197&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reuters | New Zealand Ends &amp;lsquo;COVID-Free&amp;rsquo; Status; Ackland Back in Lockdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-53796434&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BBC | Jacinda Ardern Delay Election Over Coronavirus Fears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/07/business/sweden-economy-coronavirus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Times | Sweden Has Become the World&amp;rsquo;s Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/07/business/sweden-economy-coronavirus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our World in Data | Scandinavian COVID-19 Population-Adjusted Death Rate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heparin-induced_thrombocytopenia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia | Heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (NIT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;12&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/what-antibody-studies-can-tell-you-and-more-importantly-what-they-cant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ProPublica | What Antibody Studies Can Tell You — and More Importantly, What They Can’t &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;13&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/sweden-under-fire-for-relaxed-coronavirus-approach-heres-the-science-behind-it-134926&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Conversation | Sweden under fire for ‘relaxed’ coronavirus approach – here’s the science behind it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Impact of COVID-19 on Retail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-08-15-covid-impact-retail-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-08-15-covid-impact-retail-sales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a genius to know that 2020 has been a year for the United States economy. Tens of millions were encouraged or forced to remain indoors in an attempt to slow the spread. Only a few industries/businesses were allowed to stay open, as they were classified as &amp;ldquo;essential businesses.&amp;rdquo; The longest expansion in U.S. history came to an end in Q1 2020, which resulted in a -5.0% contraction in economic activity (followed by a -32.9% drop in Q2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the same period, retail sales declined -0.87% YoY for Q1 2020, equating to a ~5 billion drop. During the second quarter, sales dropped a whopping 8.16% YoY, resulting in an approximately 12 billion decline in retail sales. (although the quarterly decline in sales is the largest since the Great Recession, the monthly decline is the largest in history)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, during the last two months, retail sales have recovered to pre-recession levels, and total sales are the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/retailsales2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;Retail Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As everyone across the country is adjusting to a life with COVID, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see which industries benefit the most, and which industries are the most impacted. The Census Bureau publishes data on Advanced Monthly Sales for Retail and Food Services; statistics are gathered utilizing a stratified random sampling method that tracks approximately 5,500 retail and food service firms. The data is then weighted and benchmarked to represent a complete universe of over three million retail and food service firms. The data goes as far back as 1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/monthly_retail_sales_2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;Monthly Retail Sales 2020&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw a slight decline in February, which can be seen as a result of seasonality (a decline as a result of holiday shopping MoM). However, during the two months afterward, we&amp;rsquo;ve experienced some extreme declines in retail sales, most of which occurred in April. Most states haven&amp;rsquo;t instituted their lockdowns until the end of March or the beginning of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retail-sales-pre-lockdown&#34;&gt;Retail Sales Pre-Lockdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2020, retail sales declined -0.44% MoM. The only industries which experienced growth were general merchandise, sporting goods/hobby stores, pharmacies/drug stores, fuel dealers, beer/liquor stores, electronic retail, and nonstore retailers. Nonstore retailers are essentially any business the primarily sells merchandise online, the industry with the largest monthly growth of 1.2%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/february_2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;February Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant declines include gasoline stations (-2.95%), men&amp;rsquo;s clothing stores (-2.86%), automotive parts (-2.38%), general clothing stores (-1.8%), and building material/suppliers dealers (-1.63%). Out of 30 NAICS industries, just seven experienced sales growth for the entire month of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retail-sales-post-lockdown&#34;&gt;Retail Sales Post-Lockdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2020, retail sales declined -14.7%; just two industries are experiencing growth during the lockdown: electronic shopping/mail-order houses and nonstore retailers. To be expected, as non-essential businesses are forced to close down, and people are encouraged to work from home if they are able. Social distancing policies instituted by state and local governments fueled demand for products designed to help people work from home and keep in contact with loved ones, such as computers, webcams, desks, monitors, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/april_2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;April Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would also assume that industries such as grocery and fast food would see some growth during this period, considering these are classified as essential businesses. However, grocery and fast food industries experienced a -13.37% and -34.32% decline, respectively. This decline could be attributed to safety concerns (unable to implement the necessary infrastructure to continue operating safely). It could be due to the decrease in mobility (many of the food and drinking places include restaurants and bars, which people can no longer patronize).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that both of these industries took a subtaintial hit. There is a reason why the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) allowed even large resturant chains to recieve loans, despite the program being designed specifically for small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the United States is a service-oriented economy. Fewer people moving around generally implies fewer money-making opportunities for businesses, regardless of industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retail-sales-after-reopening&#34;&gt;Retail Sales After Reopening&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;reopening&amp;rdquo; is a somewhat subjective term at this point, we can say that relative to the initial lockdowns, most states have started to liberalize their economies. Like Florida, most states lifted its lockdown at the beginning of May, while others such as New York and New Jersey waited until the beginning of June. Some states, such as South Dakota, never instituted a lockdown at all. As such, we can spot the growth of the recovery at the exact movement states began to reopen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/may_2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;May Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During May, Retail sales grew 18.27%, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising to anyone if you shut down the economy for nearly two months. Also, every industry experienced sales growth, which also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising. If you&amp;rsquo;re at rock bottom, the only place left to go is up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/top_sales_may_2020.png&#34; alt=&#34;Top 10 Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top 5 industries with the most growth in May include shoe stores, clothing accessories, clothing stores, women&amp;rsquo;s clothing, and sporting goods. An obvious explanation would consist of the resurgence of warmer weather. People are forced to remain inside, and it&amp;rsquo;s challenging to keep doing in a more temperate climate. Plenty of clothing stores also reopened just in time for the summer season; so the surge in sales also coincides a change in climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A not so obvious explanation would include a change in habits such as eating and exercising. Being forced to remain indoors, we&amp;rsquo;re probably eating more than usual and not exercising as often (considering the gyms are closed). Combined with all of the stress that everyone is going through, people are most likely gaining more weight. As such, they are probably shopping for clothes that fit or making adjustments to a current wardrobe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-most-covid-proof-industries&#34;&gt;The Most COVID-Proof Industries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the investing world, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to find industries that are &amp;ldquo;recession-proof.&amp;rdquo; Finding industries that are immune to pandemics, COVID in particular, is especially tricky. We want to figure out which industries performed the best ( or worse) during the first half of 2020. For this, we&amp;rsquo;re going to calculate the percentage change from January to June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/percentage_change_retail.png&#34; alt=&#34;Change Retail Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you were in the business of selling electronics and sporting goods, you most likely saw a lot of business. Interestingly, people have pointed out that liquor stores are not an essential business but noticed they were exempt from many shelters in place orders. There are most likely technical reasons for this (alcohol is still technically food), historical reasons (the prohibition era), and personal reasons (it helps reduces stress).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you owned a department store, a place where clothing and general appliances were sold, or if you owned a bar/restaurant, you most likely lost a lot of money. This is understandable; if you want to prevent the spread of a deadly virus, then you&amp;rsquo;re not going to keep places where people have to be within close proximity open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/online_retail.png&#34; alt=&#34;Change Retail Sales&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, we see a temporary bifurcation of the retail market. For as long as we are following CDC safety guidelines, only industries that are considered the most &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; and essential will outperform. If your business requires people to travel, be near one another, and require physical inventory, these industries will most likely take a hit until we&amp;rsquo;ve controlled the spread of this virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we need consider the possibility that some of the businesses that were forced to close may never repoen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the current situation has made the traditional way of engaging in commerce inconvenient, plenty of businesses have found ways to accommodate their customers (such as no-contact delivery). These days, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to have an online presence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Already Fund Education More Than Law Enforcement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-06-17-we-fund-teachers-not-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2020-06-17-we-fund-teachers-not-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may not believe it, but it&amp;rsquo;s true. We currently already spend, on aggregate (at the state and local level), more on teachers and education more than we spend on police and law enforecement. But who says we aren&amp;rsquo;t, and why does this matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give you Exhibit A:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- tweet 1269662790744145925 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we have the anatomy of a viral tweet: an emotional platitude, factually inaccurate, and a rallying cry to address a problem that currently does not exist. To be fair, maybe Benjamin Dixon is trying to tell us what we should NOT be doing. As in, we should NOT get to a point where we are funding Police more than Teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s fair, and most people would agree with that. As a thought experiment, I decided to look at economic statistics to analyze the ratio of the levels we&amp;rsquo;re spending on Police relative to Teachers. So, as usual, I took to Python [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/police_expenditures.png&#34; alt=&#34;Police Expenditures&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the output of our code is the historical Government Current Expenditures at the state and local level of law enforcement. This data goes back to 1959. As of 2018, we currently spend 137 billion dollars on police [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. (Note: much of these data comes from FRED, although it sourced by the BEA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1960, we were spending ~2 billion dollars on police. That&amp;rsquo;s is a 6,750% increase in 60 years. Faster than the rate of inflation last time I checked. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has spending on Education managed to keep the same pace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/teachers_expenditures.png&#34; alt=&#34;Teachers Expenditures&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this plot looks the same as the police expenditures plot, but the y-axis is ten times larger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we should place both time series on the same plot so we can see what&amp;rsquo;s really going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/teachers_police.png&#34; alt=&#34;Teachers and Police&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like we&amp;rsquo;re spending more on Police than we are on Teachers. Not anywhere close. Based on what I&amp;rsquo;m looking at, what we spend on law enforcement is significantly dwarfed by the amount we spend on education (as it should be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why does this narrative persist? Why do people believe that we&amp;rsquo;re not spending enough on education? I give you Exhibit B:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- tweet 1272944264608169987 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is this interesting perception among the #defundthepolice proponents is that Americans should be spending more on social services (including education), and the only reason we can&amp;rsquo;t do that is because so much of current government expenditures is already allocated towards law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the meme above, the police take up a large portion of the budget. The reduction in funding for police would naturally be offset by other government programs, such as Housing, Education, Health Care, reinvestments, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, a reduction in police spending &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; increase spending for other things; however, we already spend significantly more on other things relative to the police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/social_spending_police.png&#34; alt=&#34;Social Spending&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should indeed be spending more on all of the things that would probably reduce crime. However, there is currently nothing preventing us from doing this, especially not the police. If you compare the United States to Europe, we find that most European countries are more generous with welfare and social spending. However, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do with how much they spend on police.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As President Obama&amp;rsquo;s Council of Economic Adviser pointed out, while the United States has more correctional officers and far more prisoners than the average country, it has 35 percent fewer police officers [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/polce_v_prison.png&#34; alt=&#34;Police vs Prison&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current problem with our relationship with police in society is that they&amp;rsquo;re too unaccountable, have too much job security, and have far too little training. In fact, I would argue that that in order for police to recieve more training, they need &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; funding, not less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As state and local governments take steps towards reducing the level of funding from their law enforcement, we can expect the fewer people employed in these fields. Violent crime is currently at a 50 year low. One could make the argument, given this trend, that we no longer need the amount of police in our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if one is going to argue that police have no role in maintaining safe streets, they&amp;rsquo;re also arguing against lots of strong evidence. One of the most robust, most uncomfortable findings in criminology is that putting more officers on the street leads to less violent crime [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Notebooks/police_v_education.html&#34;&gt;Kid Quant | Replicating the data from this post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Federal Reserve Economic Database (FRED)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/whitehouse.gov/files/documents/CEA%2BCriminal%2BJustice%2BReport.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Obama White House (2016)  | Economic Perspectives on Incarceration and the Criminal Justice System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mason.gmu.edu/~atabarro/TerrorAlertProofs.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Klick &amp;amp; Tabarrok (2005) | Using terror alert levels to estimate the effect of police on crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.upenn.edu/live/files/8949-179jrss831pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Klick, MacDonald, &amp;amp; Grunwald (2015) | The effect of private police on crime: evidence from a geographic regression discontinuity design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://mason.gmu.edu/~atabarro/TerrorAlertProofs.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mello (2018) | More COPS, Less Crime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0157223&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MacDonald, Fagan, &amp;amp; Geller (2016) | The effects of local police surges on crime and arrest in New York City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholars.org/sites/scholars/files/ssn_basic_facts_rosenfeld_on_hot_spot_policing.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rosenfeld (2013) | Focusing police efforts on &amp;ldquo;hot spots&amp;rdquo; reduces crime - and can prevent it, too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libra is the Future of Money</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-10-25-libra-is-the-future-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-10-25-libra-is-the-future-of-money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you were able to catch the Congressional testimony on Facebook&amp;rsquo;s new project Libra and the Calibra wallet, probably didn&amp;rsquo;t learn a ton about the latest technology; it&amp;rsquo;s benefits; it&amp;rsquo;s detriments, and how it will be integrated into our 21st-century economy [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. Listing to the Congressional hearing, one might get the impression that Facebook is the cause for every single one of the problems we face in this country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although regulators may not care about how the new Libra project will benefit (or affect) our economy, you, the consumer, needs to know what this means for you. Anyone living in China (or visitors to China) has already seen the future. In most major metropolitan Chinese cities, you no longer need to walk around with a wallet. Your cell phone or mobile device allows you to purchase food from street vendors, pay to wash your clothes at a laundry mat, and purchase items in a grocery store. Even the street beggers will not accept your money unless it&amp;rsquo;s done via QR code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, if America does not innovate, its future in financial leadership is not guaranteed. Digital payments are happening worldwide, whether the US government likes it or not, whether you like Facebook or not. Despite the blatant grandstanding from our elected officials on the tech-giant, other concerns with the project are related to privacy, centralization, and the lack of self-sovereignty and are therefore skeptical of libra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Libra-is-the-Future-of-Money/alipay_china.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;China Alipay&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are legitimate concerns; however, they do not really matter in the grand scheme of things. I can tell you first hand that the family running the Chinese restaurant on my street corner doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about any of those things. However, they &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have Facebook, and so do all of their customers. Right now, the restaurant only accepts cash for their services. If they suddenly decide to take payment with nearly zero fees without having to handle cash, there&amp;rsquo;s no doubt in my mind that they will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-shift-to-a-cashless-soceity-is-already-mainstream&#34;&gt;The Shift to a Cashless Soceity is Already Mainstream.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries such as Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Finland are largely cashless countries; both individuals and retail stores continue to embrace online payment systems. Norway has the lowest cash usage in Europe thanks to companies like Vipps, which is used by two-thirds of the Norwegian population [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire for convenience is also beneficial. Once the average person starts adopting online payments into their life, paper bills and coin-filled pockets only become an annoyance. So now the important question is, &amp;ldquo;would we rather have a global digital currency controlled by governments or let a company like Facebook bootstrap it?&amp;rdquo; Is it really bad for crypto-enthusiast? I don&amp;rsquo;t really think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sins-of-the-past&#34;&gt;Sins of the Past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that Facebook had a rough 2018 would be an understatement. In March 2018, it was discovered that 50 million Facebook users had their private data compromised in one of the worst data privacy breaches in history, for what is currently known as the Cambridge Analytica scandal. The data extracted has been used to build psychological profiles to influence elections around the world. Ultimately, CEO Mark Zuckerberg was forced to attend a Congressional hearing regarding the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, in May 2018, it was revealed that Facebook was establishing a blockchain division that would run under the supervision of David Marcus, who had earlier overseen the creation of Facebook Messenger. This happened four months after Zuckerberg stated in his new year resolution post that he wanted Facebook to &amp;ldquo;go more in-depth and study the positive and negative aspects of cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in December 2018, news came out that Facebook was building a cryptocurrency, which would make it easier for them to transfer money on Whatsapp. The initial focus would be in India since they have 400 million Whatsapp users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in June 2019, Facebook formally announced Libra and released its whitepaper [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;]. The coin is set to launch in 2020 of next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reaching-out-to-the-unbanked&#34;&gt;Reaching Out to the Unbanked&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Libra-is-the-Future-of-Money/unbanked_population.png&#34; alt=&#34;The unbanked population&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the real power of cryptocurrencies and why Facebook&amp;rsquo;s initiative could be a game-changer, we need to understand one of the most significant issues in the financial world. Business Insider reported back in August 2017 that more than 2 billion people around the globe lack access to a bank account [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]. Other interesting information regarding the unbanked population also includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 20% of unbanked adults received wages or government transfers in cash. Also, a significant number of people in developing nations pay bills and school fees in cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women make up just over half (55%) of the unbanked population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are ~438 million people without a bank account in Southeast Asia alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India, which is the target market for Libra, has ~190 million people without bank accounts, which is the second-largest in the world after China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that there are ~5 billion people with mobile phones and ~2.38 billion Facebook users globally, the company is in a unique position to help those without access to banking services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-libra-and-what-it-isnt&#34;&gt;What is Libra, and What it isnt&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libra has five essential features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built on a secure, scalable, and reliable blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stable coin, backed by a reserve of assets, which will be less volatile than traditional cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is governed by the Libra Association, which is a consortium of different companies associated with the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will use the LibraBFT consensus mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart contract coding is done through &amp;ldquo;Move&amp;rdquo; programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook aims to have 100 members in its Libra Association before the launch. Final decision-making authority lies with the association, but Facebook will maintain a leadership role throughout 2019. However, the whitepaper states that once the network launches, all the members of the association will have the same commitments, privileges, and financial obligations as any other founding member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the peers will have equal governing power. Facebook has built a digital wallet called &amp;ldquo;Calibra,&amp;rdquo; which will be used to interact with Libra. Users will be able to send Libra via their smartphones by using the Calibra wallet. Facebook will also allow you to select from a list of partner payment providers, such as MasterCard, Visa, Paypal, and Stripe. Customers will also be able to convert US dollars into Libra for their Calibra digital wallet through local or online currency exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Libra-is-the-Future-of-Money/libra_association.png&#34; alt=&#34;Libra Association&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also worth noting that to join the Libra association and become a validator node, each member needs to pay a minimum of 10 million as Libra reserve. The Libre reserve will be used to back the intrinsic value of the libra token. Libre also adopts the LibreBFT consensus protocol and is expected to run with 100 validator nodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-libra-blockchain&#34;&gt;The Libra Blockchain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Libra blockchain is not really a blockchain in the traditional sense. For those who are not familiar, a blockchain is a series of blocks which contains time-stamped data. Each block is linked to the other cryptographically, and the data inside is kept cryptographically secure. Miners in Bitcoin and Ethereum bunch up transaction data and put them in blocks and adds them to the blockchain via the proof-of-work consensus mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libra completely changes this by not having blocks as the core data structure in its architecture. Instead, their system has been described as a &amp;ldquo;decentralized, programmable database.&amp;rdquo; The transactions in Libra will form the sequence (numbered with ever-increasing integers), which will be stored in Merkle Trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Libra-is-the-Future-of-Money/blockchain.png&#34; alt=&#34;Blockchain example&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data structure that you see above is a Merkle tree. In the diagram shown, Hash 0-0 and 0-1 are children of Hash 0, which is known as the parent. The top hash is also known as the root, and you can derive the whole tree through the root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Libra, the root of their Merkle Tree will have an authenticator value, which is similar to the block hash in a normal blockchain. The authenticator of the transaction will depend on the authenticator of the previous transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebook team decided to code their chain from scratch for it to fulfill the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to scale to billions of accounts, which requires high transaction throughput, low latency, and an efficient, high-capacity storage system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly secure, to ensure the safety of funds and financial data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flexability, so that it can power the Libra ecosystem&amp;rsquo;s governance as well as future innovation in financial services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transaction-structure-and-fees&#34;&gt;Transaction Structure and Fees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical Libra transaction has the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The account address of the transaction sender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public key that corresponds to the private key used to sign the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A script coded in Move to execute the transaction along with the arguments (if needed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gas price or the fees associated with the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gas limit of the transaction. This is the maximum amount of gas that the transaction can consume before it halts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, an unsigned integer that must be equal to the sequence number from the sender&amp;rsquo;s Libra account. After this, the transaction executes, the sequence number is incremented by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;properties-as-a-stablecoin&#34;&gt;Properties as a Stablecoin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libra is a stablecoin backed by a libra reserve, which is a reserve of real assets. The assets will be a collection of low-volatile assets, such as bank deposits and short-term government securities in currencies from stable and reputable central banks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook believes that an excellent form of money should follow three criteria: Medium of exchange, unit of account, and Store of value. Most cryptocurrencies lack one or all of these qualities, and Facebook is hoping to change that with Libra [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;libras-affect-on-banking&#34;&gt;Libra&amp;rsquo;s Affect on Banking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is attempting to create a world where payment providers, including banks, are partially disintermediated, which will bring about an almost free, instant international monetary transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Facebook&amp;rsquo;s ~2.4 million users embrace this currency, it could affect the role of central banks. Although the project isn&amp;rsquo;t completed yet, industry experts and investors all claim to be evaluating the impact that Libra will have on the banking system, but suggest that there will be a lot of hurdles along the path for Libra, but should it overcome those hurdles, it could be a significant disruptor for the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;theres-no-going-back&#34;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s No Going Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant issues with the crypto ecosystem is onboarding new users. Blockchain tech is still reasonably new, and there are certainly some hurdles to overcome on the path to mass adoption. But once we have billions of people suddenly able to transfer money via WhatsApp, Messenger, Instagram, and third-party Libra wallets, then millions of shops, hotels, and services around the world will also start accepting Libra coin in the same ways. It will become part of our daily lives, just as the cashless shops and vending machines in China have grown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means so much for the projects we&amp;rsquo;re already building in the blockchain space. You will be able to integrate Libra into your existing apps. Once we have more Libra users are interacting with all these blockchain applications, we can slowly introduce them to more decentralized, or privacy-focused coins. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, Libra will end up being the gateway drug to the mass adoption of significant blockchains like Bitcoin and Ethereum.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-libra-isnt-really-decentralized-is-it&#34;&gt;But Libra Isn&amp;rsquo;t Really Decentralized, Is it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Libra Association is currently a consortium of 20 organizations, and Facebook hopes to have this number grow to 100 when the blockchain launches in the first half of 2020. Is it as decentralized as Bitcoin or Ethereum? No &amp;ndash; but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be, either. Libra Blockchain is decentralized enough to be able to withstand control from any single party. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice stepping stone to a larger, fully decentralized platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-libra-doesnt-actually-launch&#34;&gt;What if Libra Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Actually Launch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Libra-is-the-Future-of-Money/mobile_thailand.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mobile payment systesm in Thailand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard about the Libra hearings in Congress, and some people are saying that this project will never see the light of day. Sure, that is always a possibility, but it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter at the end of the day. For blockchain technology to compete with the Chinese tech giants Alipay and WeChat, we are going to need a system like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Libra doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up launching, then it&amp;rsquo;s very likely we will see Libra clones pop up all over the place. And with the amount of new developer interest in Libra, other platforms are committed to launching the core technology payment technology over time, whether Facebook&amp;rsquo;s involved or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rising tide lifts all boats &amp;ndash; in this case, we&amp;rsquo;re talking billions of more people sending digital money like they never have before, from the mobile apps they already use. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see how transformative and disruptive Libra will be on a global scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.c-span.org/video/?c4824438/user-clip-fsc-hearing-libra-102319&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;C-SPAN | Congressional Financial Services Commitee on Libra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europeanpaymentscouncil.eu/news-insights/insight/taking-closer-look-norways-payment-landscape&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;European Payments Council | Norway has the lowest cash usage in Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vipps&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia | Vipps is a mobile application payment system for DNB designed phones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://libra.org/en-US/white-paper/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Libra Coin Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/the-worlds-unbanked-population-in-6-charts-2017-8?IR=T&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Business Insider | The world&amp;rsquo;s 2 billion unbanked population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;http://clic.cengage.com/uploads/9a535dfe28fb475252a9b35d0470a68a_1_8063.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What makes money&amp;hellip; money?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How The Beveridge Curve Reveals Current Labor Market Bifurcation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-10-10-latest-jolts-survey-shows-labor-market-bifurcation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-10-10-latest-jolts-survey-shows-labor-market-bifurcation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talks these days about an economic slow down that could potentially occur in the United States. If this is true, the evidence of this has yet to appear in the labor market. The BLS posted an unemployment rate of 3.5% for September 2019, down 0.2% from the previous month. The economy also created 136,000 jobs, which is slightly less than what was expected, previous months were revised upwards [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was initially assumed that the unemployment couldn&amp;rsquo;t go much lower, due to something called NAIRU: the &lt;strong&gt;Non-Accelerating Inflation Rate of Unemployment&lt;/strong&gt;. Without getting into deep economic theory, NAIRU (not to be confused with the natural unemployment rate) describes the level at which it would be difficult for the unemployment rate to decline, due to the inability of firms to attract new talent at the prevailing market wage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, the only way to attract new workers would be to raise wages, which would force firms to rates prices to offset their cost, which would raise consumer prices overall. Are the historical lows of the unemployment rate evidence of further slack in the labor market?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-jolts-tell-us&#34;&gt;What does JOLTS tell us?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JOLTS, or the Jobs Openings and Labor Turnovers Survey, is another measure of labor utilization, similar to the establishment and population surveys of the BLS [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. The survey tracks job openings, hires, and total separations (whether voluntary or involuntary) of the labor force. The BLS reports JOLTS with a two-month lag, as opposed to the employment situation, which is reported with a one-month lag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;job-openings&#34;&gt;Job Openings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total job openings for August 2019 were reported at 7.05 million, which is lower the 7.34 million print during the same time a year ago. This brings the job openings rate to 4.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hires&#34;&gt;Hires&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total hires were reported at 5.77 million, again lower than the 5.82 million figure posted a year ago. The hires for August is 3.8%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;separations&#34;&gt;Separations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separations are reported in two different categories: quits and layoffs. The number of quits decreased in August to 3.52 million; however, still the highest level ever. At the same time, the number of layoffs was 1.78 million. Altogether, the number of separations for August is
5.63 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings the quits rate to 2.3%, the layoffs rate to 1.2%, and the total separations rate to 3.7%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beveriedge-curve&#34;&gt;Beveriedge Curve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conventional economic wisdom tells us that there is an inverse relationship between the job openings rate and the unemployment rate. Why is this; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t more employment generally lead to fewer job vacancies? This is not necessarily the case. Higher unemployment is usually associated with recessions, and when recessions occur, firms are less likely to expand their workforce; hence, a lower job openings rate. The relationship can be illustrated in what is known as &lt;strong&gt;The Beveridge Curve&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Latest-JOLTS-Survey/Beveridge_Curve.png&#34; alt=&#34;Beveridge Curve Plot&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Beveridge Curve plots the job openings rate with respect to the unemployment rate [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]. During an expansion, the job openings rate is high, and the unemployment rate is low, which causes the curve to move towards plots upward and to the left. During a contraction, the job openings rate is low, and the unemployment rate is high, which causes a movement along the curve in the opposite direction.  Basic Econ 101, pretty much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we all learn in Econ 101, things become more interesting when we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with &lt;em&gt;shifts&lt;/em&gt; in the curve, which can indicate a structural change in the economy. This shift can be due to industry-based structural mismatching or geographical changes. If we examine the relationship between unemployment and job openings, this appears to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Latest-JOLTS-Survey/plotted_beveridge_curve.png&#34; alt=&#34;Beveridge Curve Plot&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following Beveridge Curve is one that I have created in python, using data from the Federal Reserve Economic Database (FRED), which was extracted through Quandl [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would seem that the curve started to shift around 2010, a couple of months after the end of the Great Recession. However, when the recovery started in 2009, the curve did not retrace the previous pattern from 2000-2009. What does this shift in The Beveridge Curve mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can look back at a random period from nearly 20 years ago when the unemployment rate was near 4.0%. The job openings rate hovered around 3.0%. More than a decade later, the job openings rate increased to 4.5% with the same level of unemployment. So, for any level of unemployment (horizontal axis), there appears to be a higher rate of job openings (vertical axis).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 10 years after the Great Recession, employers seem to be reluctant to fill their job openings. Put it another way, it appears that employers are having a difficult time finding a match when posting job opportunities, whether internally or externally. Following periods of economic decline, it isn&amp;rsquo;t uncommon to find high levels of unqualified candidates. This mismatch usually lasts about three years, on average, according to some research [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, the unemployment rate is near historic lows. Who could possibly suffer from this structural shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-first-big-break-after-college&#34;&gt;Your First Big Break After College&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should go without saying that college graduates do relatively well compared to those without a college degree. Also, people who graduate into a strong labor market are more likely to earn more through their careers than people who join the labor market during a recession. According to data from the New York Federal Reserve, the unemployment rate for recent college graduates is 3.8% [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Latest-JOLTS-Survey/un_rate_college_20_24.png&#34; alt=&#34;Unemployment Rate College Grads&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the BLS shows that the unemployment rate for college graduates between the age of 20 - 24 is around 6.1%, which is nearly double the national average. As you can see from the following chart, the data is very noisy; dropping during the beginning of the year and rising towards the middle (usually the summer). This is because, as you can imagine, during the beginning of the year, students are actively enrolled in school, so they aren&amp;rsquo;t counted as part of the labor market. Once they graduate (usually during the summer), they begin actively looking for work. From that point onward, recent graduates are officially counted among the unemployment statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real cause of concern may be the &lt;em&gt;underemployment rate,&lt;/em&gt; which describes a situation where workers of high skill levels and high educational attainment are working in relatively low-skilled, low-wage jobs. This rate usually varies, but Gallup estimates that the underemployment rate is somewhere around 12.1% [&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;]. This all ties into the shift in the Beveridge curve, and why employers are more reluctant to fill their job openings. But why is this the case? How do we know that the shortfall of recent college graduates has caused this shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;entry-level-not-so-entry&#34;&gt;Entry-Level Not So Entry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/talent.works/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/entry-level-jobs-years-experience-1.png?w=1067&amp;amp;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;3 years of experience for your first job&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prevailing, and yet and unfortunately, Catch-22 persists in the labor market. Some firms won&amp;rsquo;t hire you without the necessary (or related) experience; however, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get the required experience if the firms aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to take a chance on you. As our economy becomes more specialized and highly competitive, it would seem that this issue will continue to persist.  Some research conducted by Kushal Chakrabarti of TalentWorks has found that 61% of all entry-level jobs require 3+ years of experience [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;]? How can this be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process was rather simple. A random sample of 95,363 jobs was analyzed. From there, you can parse through the types of jobs being offered and the experience they require. Some interesting details were discovered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of experience required for any position increases by 2.8% every year. At this rate, the graduating class of 2032 will need 4 years of experience just to get their first job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With those three years of experience, you will qualify for roughly 75% of all entry-level jobs being offered. An extreme difference from the labor market conditions of our parents, who could be eligible for most entry-level jobs with merely a college diploma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very few of the entry-level jobs you&amp;rsquo;ll find on websites such as LinkedIn or Indeed (LinkedIn is the largest culprit of this in my experience) are actually entry-level positions. These days, internships are considered the new entry-level job [&lt;a href=&#34;#10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i1.wp.com/talent.works/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/job-search-pain-in-the-ass-1.png?w=2280&amp;amp;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;Time Spent Looking For Work&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what gives? Why are so many firms trying to discourage recent college graduates from applying to what should be entry-level positions? Maybe recent college grads are just unprepared for the workplace. That certainly seems to be the view of most employers, according to a survey conducted by the National Association of College and Employers (NACE) [&lt;a href=&#34;#11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of this survey indicate that college graduates tend to overestimate their abilities when it comes to areas like professionalism, work ethic, oval/written communication, and critical thinking skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.insidehighered.com/sites/default/server_files/media/Chart1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Recent College Grads Survey&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether this is true or not, the fact that employers believe this is true presents an obstacle for recent college grads. Today, employers are getting impatient, and they prefer workers who don&amp;rsquo;t need to be trained to do their jobs. We can also come up with a plethora of other reasons for this disparity. Still, this issue is significantly related to the shift in The Beveridge Curve, a mismatch between the skills employers require the skills the workforce possesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-be-done-if-it-should-be-done&#34;&gt;What Can Be Done, If It Should Be Done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s unclear what can be done about this structural change if there is anything at all that can be done about it. Is it unreasonable to ask employers to become more realistic about the job requirements for the jobs they offer? Should our universities start reducing the number of curriculums that are impractical and a waste of time? I don&amp;rsquo;t have the answers to these questions; however, we do know that there is an evident labor market inefficiency that isn&amp;rsquo;t going away. For whatever reason, employers are posting more job openings but don&amp;rsquo;t like what they&amp;rsquo;re seeing among possible candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources-a-name1a&#34;&gt;Sources &lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics | Employment Situation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/jolts.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bureau of Labor Statistics | Jobs Openings and Labor Turnovers Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beveridge_curve&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia | The Beveridge Curve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://fred.stlouisfed.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Federal Reserve Economic Database (FRED)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quandl.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quandl | The world&amp;rsquo;s most powerful database&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.richmondfed.org/publications/research/econ_focus/2018/q3/feature1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Richmond Federal Reserve | Help Wanted: Employers are having a hard time hiring. Not enough workers or not the right skills?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorkfed.org/research/college-labor-market/college-labor-market_unemployment.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Federal Reserve Bank of New York | Unemployment Rates for College Graduates and Other Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://smartasset.com/retirement/how-many-americans-are-underemployed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SmartAssets | How many Americans are Underemployed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://talent.works/2018/03/28/the-science-of-the-job-search-part-iii-61-of-entry-level-jobs-require-3-years-of-experience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TalentWorks | The science of the job search - Part III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/grade-point/wp/2015/05/18/are-internships-the-only-way-for-recent-college-grads-to-grab-entry-level-jobs/?noredirect=on&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Washington Post | Are internships the only way for recent college grads to grab entry level jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.naceweb.org/job-market/trends-and-predictions/job-outlook-fall-recruiting-for-the-class-of-2018/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Association of College and Employers | Job Outlook: Fall recruiting for the class of 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling GDP per Capita and Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-09-18-modeling-gdp-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2019-09-18-modeling-gdp-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Historically, wealthy individuals tend to live longer than poorer individuals, holding other factors constant. They can afford to eat healthier foods from healthier food outlets (such as Whole Foods); they can afford better health care, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, it should be obvious that as countries get wealthier that they should be able to afford better health care systems, also that life expectancy should rise. It should also stand to reason htat people living longer, will work longer and that being healthier means fewer people as a propotion drop out of the labor force due to illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, these relationships probably are not linearly. They&amp;rsquo;re likely to be diminishing returns to one from the other. At least, that is my prior belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first hypothesis is that returns to life expectancy at birth from increases in Gross Domesti Product (GDP) per capita are deminishing. This is because there is probably an upper limit on the length of human life and that approaching it is more difficult the closer humans reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it is easy to concieve nations consuming more unhealthy luxury items as they become richer. Therefore, I expect the coefficient on GDP per capita to be positive and the coefficient of GDP per capital squared to be negative in the regression of life expectancy on the GDP per capita variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second hypothesis is that returns to GDP per capita from increases in life expectacy are diminishing. Therefore, I expect the coefficient of life expectancy to be positive and coefficient of life expectancy squared to be negative in the regression of GDP per capita on life expectancy and life expectancy squared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test these hypothesses, I repeatedly estimate those models over crosssections in my sample period using Ordinary Least Squared (OLS) regression. Finally, I plotted the model coefficients over time to see if the relationships have changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already tons of literature on this question, but I chose not to research it because it did not want bias to approach this problem. Significance in this document is at the alpha = 0.05 level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-and-sample-period-selection&#34;&gt;Data and Sample Period Selection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used data sets from the World Bank to perform this analysis. I selected my sample period by examining the period of the missing values and choosing long time periods with as few missing observations as possible. This seemed to be the period from 1990 to 2017. Removing observations that weren&amp;rsquo;t real countries (mainly regional and world-wide averages) and performing an inner join between two variables on the sample period left about three quarters of our countries in our data set, of 163 observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/missing_percent.png&#34; alt=&#34;Missing post&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plotting-our-variables-of-interest&#34;&gt;Plotting our Variables of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is how the life expectancy at birth for the world has changed over the years. It has increased steadily over the years, which is good for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/world_life_expectancy.png&#34; alt=&#34;World Life Expectancy&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This histogram is representative of the distribution of life expectancy in 2017. The mass of the distribution is on the right with a long left tail. This is good because there are more countries living longer than countries with lower life expectancy levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/life_expectancy_distribution.png&#34; alt=&#34;Life Expectancy Distribution&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World GDP per capita has grown exponentially over time, but there are some sharp drops from severe negative shocks. This is still a good thing for humanity because it means fewer people as a percentage of the total population are in poverty compared to years prior. Again, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell us about the distribution of GDP per capita in a cross section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/world_life_expectancy_2019.png&#34; alt=&#34;World Life Expectancy in 2019 dollars&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of GDP per capita is very concentrated in the 0 to 10,000ish range, but has a long right tail out to over 100,000 GDP per capita. This resembles a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Log-normal_distribution&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;log-normal&lt;/a&gt; shape. I performed a natural logarithmic transformation for modeling purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/log_distribution_life_expectancy.png&#34; alt=&#34;Log-normal Distribution&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modeling-the-relationships&#34;&gt;Modeling the Relationships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jupyter Notebook I&amp;rsquo;ve created contains all the regression outputs for every year; however, I&amp;rsquo;ll just summarize them and provide the plots of the coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regressing-life-expectancy-on-gdp-per-capita&#34;&gt;Regressing Life Expectancy on GDP per capita&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The residuals of this model seem mildly skewed left from 1990 to 2003, and a strong left skew after that with kurtosis in excess of the normal distribution. We won&amp;rsquo;t really get into what &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kurtosis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;kurtosis&lt;/a&gt; is in this blog post, but you should know that in probability and statistics, kurtosis measures the &amp;ldquo;tailedness&amp;rdquo; of a probability distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kurtosis of a normal distribution is 3, so any value greater than that will exhibit skewness either to the left or right. The output of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breusch%e2%80%93Pagan_test&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Breusch-Pagan heteroskedasticity test&lt;/a&gt; provides strong evidence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heteroscedasticity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heteroskedasticity&lt;/a&gt; in the residuals, but I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heteroscedasticity-consistent_standard_errors&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heteroskedasticity robust standard errors&lt;/a&gt; to be sure the model didn&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the standard errors of the coefficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the residuals are not normally or identically distributed. The Durbin-Watson statistic remains close to 2, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be auto-correlation in our residuals. The R-squared, $r^{2}$, of these regressions are absurdly high, ranging from 0.992 to 0.997; meaning, between 99.2% to 99.7% of the variation in life expectancy is explained by this model specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/coefficient_gdppc.png&#34; alt=&#34;GDPPC&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/coefficient_gdppc_sq.png&#34; alt=&#34;GDPPC_SQ&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;regressing-gdp-per-capita-on-life-expectancy&#34;&gt;Regressing GDP per capita on Life Expectancy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The residuals of this model seem approximately symmetric throughout the entire period, as the skewness stays between -0.5 and 0.5. The kurtosis remains fairly close to that of the normal distribution but does exceed it in some periods. The Jarque-Bera test for normality fails to reject the null hypothesis of normality from 1993 to 2007, and from 2015 to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the break in the string of models with normal residuals is related to the 2007 financial crisis and recovery. The output of the Breusch-Pagan heteroskedasticity test give strong evidence of heteroskedasticity in the residuals, but I used heteroskedasticity robust standard errors to be sure the model didn&amp;rsquo;t underestimate the standard errors of the efficients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So our residuals are occasionally not normally or identically distributed in our sample period. The Durbin-Watson statistic remains close to 2, so at least there doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be auto-correlation in our residuals. The $r^{2}$ of these models range from 0.985 to 0.993, meaning between 98.5% to 99.3% of the variation in the natural log of GDP per capita is explained by this model specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coefficient in the model are sigificant in each year, but are both positive, &lt;strong&gt;disproving my second hypothesis. There are positive, and increasing returns to the &lt;em&gt;ln&lt;/em&gt;(GDP per capita) from increases in life expectancy in our sample period.&lt;/strong&gt; Plotting the coefficient with their 95% confidence interval bars over the sample period show they appear somewhat volatile over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a straight line that intersects all of the confidence intervals. In a 27 sample period, we would expect a 95% confidence interval to not contain the true parameter 0.05 x 27 = 1.35 times, but it seems 10 periods might barely miss a horizontal line that tries to hit as many intervals as possible. Still, this isn&amp;rsquo;t conclusive evidence that the relationship between GDP per capita and life expectancy has changed over the 27 year period. Just a strong clue to dig deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/error_bars.png&#34; alt=&#34;error bars&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot of the life expectancy squared coefficients looks like it is mirroring the movement of the non-squared term coefficients at a different scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/error_bars_sq.png&#34; alt=&#34;error bars squared&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interpreting-the-regressions&#34;&gt;Interpreting the Regressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the scatter plots below for the most recent data (2017), along with the regression lines, show that the variables have a relationship with one another. Also, there is more variability among the lower and middle-income countries than the high-income countries. Explaining the differences between low and middle-income countries with higher levels of life expectancy versus lower life expectancy levels seems like an interesting avenue of research that could provide important insights into interventions that could help improve people&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/non_linear_regression.png&#34; alt=&#34;non linear regression&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way to interpret the coefficients in the 2017 model regressing life expectancy on ln(GDP per capita) and ln(GDP per capita) squared is a 1% increase in GDP per capita leads to a year increase in life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$\hat{y}=\frac{12.1586-2&lt;em&gt;0.4300&lt;/em&gt;ln(GDP\ per\ capita)}{100}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This combines the level-log coefficient in interpretation with the interpretation of coefficients as marginal effects, aka partial derivatives, of the dependent variable with respect to the independent variable in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generically, an increase 1% in GDP per capita leads to the following increase in life expectancy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$\hat{y}=\frac{\beta_{1}+2*\beta_{2} * ln(GDP\ per\ capita)}{100}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where $\beta_{1}$ is the coefficient of the non-squared term and $\beta_{2}$ is the coefficient of the squared term. The numerator is the partial dervivative of life expectancy with respect to ln(GDP per capita). All regression coefficients are partial derivatives. I just want to emphasize that with higher order terms, you cannot correctly interrep the coefficient of $x$ seperately from $x^{2}$, where n is not 1 or 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are the modeling results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/model_results.png&#34; alt=&#34;non linear regression&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/Model-GDP-per-capita-and-life-expectancy/non_linear_regression.png&#34; alt=&#34;non linear regression&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implications&#34;&gt;Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis that higher income countries live longer, but with decreasing returns to life expectancy from additional increases in per capita income is supported by the evidence. This isn&amp;rsquo;t very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I found that increasing returns to ln(GDP per capita) from increases in life expectancy. Although, causation or a causal channel has not been established, it seems plausible that healthy workers stay in the work force longer without dropping out due to illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This in turn results in more GDP per capita growth. Perhaps there are alternate or additional pathways for the relationship as well. The results of this exploration strongly suggest that investing in better health care systems will have positive effects on the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Lie With Inflation Statistics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-lie-with-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/how-to-lie-with-inflation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inflation is probably one of the most difficult phenomena to understand. It’s such a difficult topic to understand, most people have difficulty defining it. At the very least, it can be defined as a broad increase in the average level of prices throughout the entire economy. Some people also define inflation as simply an increase in the money supply. Even more difficult than simply defining the term, most probably aren’t aware of how inflation actually occurs, which can originate through a number of different factors. I’m not going to go through them all, but economists can probably agree that inflation is not an observable phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to go through them all, but economists can probably agree that inflation is not an observable phenomenon. Well, the only exception might be if the economy was experiencing what we would refer to as ‘hyperinflation‘. In that case, inflation would be similar to pornography, you’ll know it when you see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, since individuals can’t really observe inflation, the best that we can do is try to measure it. There are many different ways to measure inflation, which means there are many different ways to measure things in real terms. This makes measuring information such as ‘real wages’ more of an art rather than a science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would probably enter “real wages are falling” into a Google search bar and find many different articles relating to wages falling in real terms. For example, this article from the Washington Post outlines how inflation has eroded the purchasing power of their wages [1].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without adjusting for inflation, these “nonsupervisory” workers saw their average hourly earnings jump 2.8 percent from last year. But that was not enough to keep pace with the 2.9 percent increase in inflation, which economists attributed to rising gas prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is very likely because of the spike in oil prices eating into inflation-adjusted earnings,” said Allen Sinai, chief global economist and strategist at Decision Economics. “We pay for energy-related costs out of our wages, out of our compensation. And it’s making a real impact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the way the authors of this article is measuring inflation, it would appear that wages are barely keeping up with inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/cpiinflation.png&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is just one thing wrong with only looking at headline inflation; the authors of the article already pointed out one of the flaws. Inflation appears to be increasing due to rising energy prices. Considering this, we should look at an inflation metric that removes the effects of rapidly increasing energy prices, such as core-CPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/ahecore.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this inflation metric, we can see that real wages aren’t falling. So why does it matter whether or not someone is going core-CPI or headline CPI? Core CPI is merely the same as headline CPI, which excludes the price changes in food and energy. This is because food and energy tend to be very volatile, which may unfairly distort how inflation is measured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The this imply that the writers of the Washington Post article, Jeff Stein and Andrew Van Dam, are lying about inflation? It doesn’t imply that they were intentionally trying to mislead. After all, using headline CPI, it is true that inflation is outpacing wage growth. However, it is possible for someone to use inflation statistics for the purposes of being misleading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/inflationindicies.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following image shows Annualized Average Hourly Earnings compared with 8 different inflation indicies: Headline and Core CPI, Headline and Core PCE, and the GDP Deflator. I’ve also included 3 alternative measures of the CPI: the Chained, Trimmed-mean and the Median CPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, some of these metrics (PCE, GDP Deflator, and the Trimmed-Mean CPI) actually show that real wages are rising, not falling. So which inflation metrics should we be using? That all depends on what people are measuring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;median-and-trimmed-mean-cpi&#34;&gt;Median and Trimmed-Mean CPI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, Core CPI (as well as PCE) throws out the most volatile price changes: food and energy. Some people may not prefer to do that, as food and energy are good and people actually purchase on a daily basis. Instead, one could use a more mathematically sophisticated price index like the median and Trimmed-Mean CPI. They achieve the same goal; however, instead of throwing out food and energy, the median and Trimmed-Mean CPI removes the items with the largest price fluctuations within a given month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could think of it as removing the outliers from a particular dataset. Instead of calculating the weighted-average basket of goods, the median CPI price changes of all goods and services. The Trimmed-Mean CPI works in a similar fashion, by removing 8% of items with the highest and lowest one-month price change, resulting in a 16% Trimmed-Mean Inflation Estimate. When looking at both of these inflation metrics, in terms of the Median CPI, wages currently in-line with inflation. In terms of Trimmed-Mean, wages are outpacing inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/trimmedmeanmedian.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gdp-deflator&#34;&gt;GDP Deflator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GDP Deflator is another lesser-known inflation metric, but still just as valid. While most inflation metrics only measure price changes of goods and services, the GDP Deflator measures the price of everything in the economy, such as investment spending in the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, businesses purchase a lot of computer equipment and computer equipment is measured as a part of GDP. As such, one could expect the prices of computer equipment to be passed on to consumers. However, the price of electronics has actually fallen over time (if you consider the amount it takes to purchase at the average industrial wage), overall price fluctuations in the GDP Deflator will tend to be smaller as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/gdpdeflator.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pce-chain-type-index&#34;&gt;PCE Chain-Type Index&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, but not least, we have the Personal Consumer Expenditure Change-Type Index (or PCE). The PCE is similar in some ways to the CPI; however, whereas the CPI measures a basket of goods and services based on out-of-pocket purchases, the PCE the same basket based on purchases by consumers and on behalf of consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, consumers may utilize an employer-based health insurance plan. This employer would purchase a policy on behalf of its employer. Or the government could purchase an insurance policy on a public/private insurance exchange on behalf of a taxpayer. This, as a result, allows statisticians to better monitor the shopping habits of consumers more closely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the PCE Chain-Type Index is the preferred metric of the Federal Reserve for this particular reason. Sure, it does look at other measures of inflation to gauge inflationary pressures in the economy. However, the FOMC is going to place a greater weight on PCE inflation when making it’s policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we look at both headline and core PCE, we find that real wages are also rising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/PCE.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, is there anything wrong with using CPI over PCE? Which inflation metric should people be using? Like everything, it always depends and it usually helps to understand how both indices weight certain goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:4321/post/images/comparison.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;your image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not actually sure about how the Bureau of Labor Statistics determines how it weighs certain items in the Consumer Price Index. However, I know that Personal Consumption Expenditure Chain-Type Index is weighed in terms of the portion someone spends on a good or services relative to overall expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, according to NIPA data from the Bureau of Economic Analysis, consumers spend roughly 20% of their income on medical care services, which is reflected in the PCE weighing. However, medical care only covers a 7% weighing in the CPI, so the price changes in the CPI will fail to reflect rising medical cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for whatever reason, shelter has a 31% weight in the CPI, but only a 15% weight in the PCE index. According to NIPA data, consumers spend roughly 17% of their income on shelter, which is in line with PCE weights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the PCE does a good job of tracking the goods and services purchased by consumers, if I’m interested in tracking inflationary pressures, I would want to place greater emphasis on the PCE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There really isn’t much of a debate centered around this topic; most of the inflation metrics listed here are legitimate and are used for different purposes. Although measuring inflation is more of an art rather than a science, selecting an inflation metric should be backed by a scientific analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, if people are going to select the PCE over the CPI (and vice versa), there needs to be a reason why. As long as there is some subjectivity with these matters, I believe this approach is a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, numbers don’t lie; however, the people who provide the numbers sure can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chart of the Day: 3-Month Bill Bid-To-Cover Ratio Plunges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2018-07-28-chart-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2018-07-28-chart-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While demand for US Treasuries remains brisk at primary auctions, the same can hardly be said for the short-end of the market, where moments ago we saw what happens to auction demand in a time of rapidly rising rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in the chart above, while the yield on the 3 month Bills auctioned off today came in largely as expected at 1.94%, the demand did not, and after an already depressed Bid-to-Cover ratio of 2.89 last week, today’s 3-month auction suffered from one of the lowest demands on record, tumbling to just 2.62. At $125.88 billion in bids tendered for $48 billion in paper, down sharply from $138.87 billion on June 25. In context, the last time the markets have witnessed a Bid-To-Cover ratio this low was post-Lehman crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With both T-Bill issuance continuing to surge, and ratings rising, two things are certain: not only will the Libor-OIS spread resume blowing out amid the continued surge in short-term supply and increasingly tighter financial conditions, but demand will continue to slide. However, the good news is that we are still well off from the record lows, in which auctions were only 2.0x covered at the start of the century. That said, who knows: perhaps the break in the bond market will begin with a failed Bill action as the US Treasury finds it increasingly difficult to roll over short-term debt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
