<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lockdowns | KidQuant</title>
    <link>https://kidquant.com/tag/lockdowns/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kidquant.com/tag/lockdowns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lockdowns</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kidquant.com/media/icon_huf195f9a67bfe19c82d5f0ba6a67922fa_2030_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lockdowns</title>
      <link>https://kidquant.com/tag/lockdowns/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York State of Decline</title>
      <link>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how New York became America&amp;rsquo;s financial center? It&amp;rsquo;s not like the New York Stock Exchange is the only securities market in the country. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s the NASDAQ (another in New York), but there is one in Miami, Chicago, and Philidelphia. In fact, Philadelphia initially obtained financial supremacy in the country with the establishment of the Bank of Pennsylvania in 1780.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I learned during my Finance undergraduate studies, it all amounts to pure luck why Philadephia isn&amp;rsquo;t America&amp;rsquo;s financial center. The main reason why economic supremacy shifted from Philly was NYC&amp;rsquo;s geographical advantage with the Erie Canal construction. The Erie Canal connected to the Hudson River to the Great Lakes and the fastest-growing places in the Appalachian Mountains. The canal helped solidify New York&amp;rsquo;s position as America&amp;rsquo;s center for commercial trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point of this history lesson: nothing lasts forever. If a country, region, state, or area loses its comparative advantage, it may also lose its overall economic advantage. Enter James Altucher, author of the &lt;em&gt;NYC is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/em&gt; article [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. He wrote a scathing rebuke of the current situation involving New York City, arguing, although the city has been through a lot, this time is different. James obviously addressed all of the crucial points, which are undeniably true. Why else would high profile individuals such as Jerry Seinfield, Mark Cuban, and Bill De&amp;rsquo;Blasio respond to an article on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say whether I agree with the points raised in the article; there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot that I can add to strengthen the &amp;ldquo;New York is Dead&amp;rdquo; argument. We can debate what it would mean for an entire city to be &amp;ldquo;dead,&amp;rdquo; whether it&amp;rsquo;s fewer people choosing to travel to NYC or high-net-worth individuals and established industries choosing to relocate to other areas. What I can say is that the threats to New York&amp;rsquo;s financial position are &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, James outlines that many people in March/April relocated when the Pandemic situation in NYC worsened; the second wave of people left when crime was spiraling out of control. Some may suggest that the stores of New Yorkers fleeing the city in droves may be greatly exaggerated [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that the COVID pandemic merely exacerbated what many New Yorkers have been feeling all along: &amp;ldquo;I gotta get out of here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows anything about living in New York understands how unfeasible it is to maintain a decent standard of living unless you&amp;rsquo;re very poor or wealthy [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_pop_change.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Population Change&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following map shows the population change of New York counties within the last 9 years. The plot measures cumulative growth since April 2010; each county is shaded in a different color. The closer the shade is to blue, the larger the population growth within the last 9 years (and vice versa). As we can see, change in the NY population has been on a steady decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the five boroughs, except Richmond County (Staten Island), are the only counties with experienced population growth within the same period, albeit very modest. Regardless, Census Bureau data suggest that NYC has been bleeding residents as early as 2016 [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t clear whether COVID and crime are the final straw for many life-long New Yorkers. Instead, the current situation has allowed people to imagine the possibility of becoming life-long somewhere-elsers. As James pointed out, people are willing to tolerate the higher taxes and cost of living because of business/employment opportunities and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_ue_rate.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Unemployment Rate&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is a plot of the same region, except this measures the August Unemployment by county. The vast majority of areas in New York have an unemployment rate similar to the national average of 8.4 percent. In stark contrast, the five boroughs (and the surrounding areas) have unemployment rates significantly above the national average, ranging from 12 percent to as high as 20 percent. This unemployment level is consistent with the severe COVID restrictions still imposed on many industries in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, NYC and New York as a whole have not experienced a second wave in the same way other cities across the globe have. Governor Cuomo once suggested that people were &amp;ldquo;fleeing other states because it&amp;rsquo;s a safe state.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] While there is nothing to indicate that people have weighed the opportunity cost of looking for work as opposed to catching COVID,. Instead, people have decided that it&amp;rsquo;s too expensive to live in NYC for all of the city&amp;rsquo;s headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be realistic; changes in mortgage rates and what people are looking for in a home provide an incentive for people who were already considering moving. The largest incentive for people living in the city (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter which city) is the cost [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. In addition, ~80 percent of NYC employees live in the five boroughs; with NYC-based firms offering more flexible work-from-home policies, that number is likely to decline [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]. Lastly, the COVID Pandemic prevents NYC residents from fully enjoying local amenities, which lowers the incentive to live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if there is no incentive to live here, there is also no incentive to conduct business here. Manhattan Borough President Gale Brewer counted 335 street-level vacancies along Broadway (a ~80 increase from three years ago), a major shopping area/tourist attraction in NYC [&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;]. Other industries are just as amenable to the effects of the pandemic as well. Still, the one affected industry that has the power to effectively reshape NYC is, of course, the &lt;strong&gt;Financial sector&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, New Yorkers (at least, NYC-based finance employees) debated where the next financial hotspot would be, and for a long time, that hotspot appeared to be Hudson Yards. Today, as work-from-home policies have reduced the need for employees in office environments, financial firms are considering reducing its physical presence by at least 20%, according to a study released by the Partnership for New York City [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same study has also pointed out that 1 in four office employers intend to reduce their footprint by at least a fifth, and about 16 percent expect to move jobs out of the city. Companies also expect only 10 percent of their employees to return to the office by the end of summer and just 40 percent by the year-end. The lack of mobility is expected to shrink economic activity by 13 percent this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a personal anecdote, I was expected to return back to the office in mid-September; however, my firm has left work-from-home optional for many employees. From what I here, the office is mostly empty, which should surprise no one. As long as resturants and businesses remain closed, as long as the number of businesses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nyc-dead-forever-heres-why-james-altucher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James Altucher | NYC Is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://nypost.com/2020/08/11/new-yorkers-flee-nyc-in-droves/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Post | New Yorkers Keep Moving To The Suburbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://money.cnn.com/calculator/pf/cost-of-living/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNBC Money | Cost of Living City Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/fredgraph.png?g=w7H1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FRED | Resident Population in NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thehill/status/1285337437867212802?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1285337437867212802%7Ctwgr%5Eshare_0&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fdw-site-staging.dailywire.com%2Fnews%2Fandrew-cuomo-claims-people-are-now-fleeing-to-new-york-because-its-safe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hill | New York State Governor Andrew Cuomo Press Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redfin.com/blog/wfh-leaving-new-york-san-francisco/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RedFin | Post-Pandemic Migration from Expensive Cities Likely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/planning/download/pdf/planning-level/housing-economy/nyc-ins-and-out-of-commuting.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NYC Planning Department | The Ins and Outs of NYC Commuting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/business-vacancies-rise-on-new-york-citys-broadway-11599652800#:~:text=Coronavirus%20pandemic%20strains%20companies%20along,street-level%20vacancies%20along%20Broadway.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal | Business Vacanies Rise on New York City&amp;rsquo;s Broadway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://pfnyc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/actionandcollaboration.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Partnership for New York City | A Call for Action and Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID Vs. Economy</title>
      <link>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-08-22-covid-vs-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-08-22-covid-vs-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about the Mathematics of Pandemics. I&amp;rsquo;ve even talked about the Politics of Pandemics. I&amp;rsquo;m long overdue to discuss the &amp;ldquo;Economics of Pandemics;&amp;rdquo; however, theorizing the potential effects of an inadequate response was pretty pointless, as anyone who has lived through the Great Recession would tell you. After all, &amp;ldquo;ignorance on fire is sometimes better than knowledge on ice,&amp;rdquo; as the saying goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether or not our economic response to COVID was sufficient, the discussion was always framed in a false dichotomy: protecting the vulnerable versus protecting the economy. If one is a pragmatic, normal-thinking individual, these two are not necessarily mutually exclusive. As early as March 27th, the IGM Chicago Forum surveyed more than 40 professional economists regarding the economic lockdowns in response to the COVID-19 crisis. The vast majority of respondents agree (88%) believe that a comprehensive policy response would involve tolerating a massive contraction in economic activity until the spread has dropped significantly (Question A) [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the United States, along with other nations around the world, instituted their lockdowns policy. We initiated our 15 Days to Slow The Spread, which quickly became 30 Days to Slow The Spread. Although most states have very minor COVID restrictions (staying six feet apart, no gatherings greater than 20 people, etc.), other places that were more severely affected are imposing more strict regulations. [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] It just so happens that the places with the strictest COVID regulation are also home to the largest economies in the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although most states have partially reopened (except for California), the U.S. economy contracted by a whopping -32.9% in the second quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that sounds like a big number, that&amp;rsquo;s because it is a big number. The Bureau of Economic Analysis calculates GDP on an annualized basis; this facilitates comparison of growth rates over various periods. In other words, the -32.9% figure is what we would get if the economy sustained its growth (or, in this case, decline) for one year. When used to measure very short-term changes (such as locking down for one or two months), it can be misleading. As such, it&amp;rsquo;s probably better to use Year-over-year change, which would record a -9.5% decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-invisible-threat-ever-lurking&#34;&gt;An Invisible Threat Ever Lurking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how economic growth is measured, the catch-22 is unavoidable. COVID is so bad, it warrants locking down the economy to control its spread, but the economy is bad because we are locked down to prevent the spread of COVID. What a paradox&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the risk of infection is very real; we can&amp;rsquo;t expect things to go back to &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; if the risk of transmission is still high. Some would point out that the economic contraction was only severe &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; we failed to control the spread of COVID. The only problem with this theory is that the United States had the slowest contraction out of all the nations which successfully controlled the spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/us_gdp_global.png&#34; alt=&#34;US vs Global GDP&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The virus ravaged Italy and Spain, and they have instituted strict lockdowns in return. Other places in Europe, which did not want to become the next Italy, instituted strict lockdowns. (Canada is included, for no other reason than it is our neighbor to the north) Some may argue that these nations made a significant trade-off; they chose to protect lives over the economy, and now the economy will be better off in the long-run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except now all of these places are relaxing their COVID restrictions and the virus is starting to spread again. Cases are starting to spike in France, while infections are slowly increasing in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/france_spain_covid.png&#34; alt=&#34;France and Spain&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following places are experiencing an uptick in COVID-19 cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spain, Italy, United Kingdom, Belgium, Neterlands, Switzerland, Greece, Portugal, Denmark, Norway, Japan, Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do all of these places have in common? These regions were assumed to be in control of the virus [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;]. Now the virus is out of control and these regions are either experiencing a large surge (Japan), or a steady increase in cases (United Kingdom). Whether by pure luck or by a fortunate circumstance, the United States experienced a phenomenon in early June that Europe should have learned in early July: &lt;strong&gt;you can&amp;rsquo;t hide from the virus forever&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the lockdowns aren&amp;rsquo;t supposed to last forever; they just need to be maintained until a vaccine is found [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. There&amp;rsquo;s no mention of when we can expect a COVID-19 anti-viral vaccine to be developed; &amp;ldquo;never&amp;rdquo; is a very realistic timeline for an effective vaccine (the flu vaccine has a 40-70% effectiveness). Regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s apparent that lockdown is not a sustainable strategy. For two reasons: 1) the obvious economic ramifications of keeping the economy locked down and 2) locking down just delays the inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, we don&amp;rsquo;t have guidelines on what it means to reopen safely, or knowledge if this is even possible because the world has never been locked down before. Lockdown is a new concept that has never been tested for efficacy or implementation. Once the virus transmission restarts, the vulnerable and susceptible are still part of the population and will simply die later rather than sooner unless effective measures are taken to protect them. The only thing that can stop transmission of the virus long term is immunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, locking down doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent an outbreak; it merely delays or pushes it out over a longer time frame depending on how severe the lockdowns were implemented. One may point out how South Korea infamously flattened the curve and controlled the spread of the virus. What really happened was that the region has been playing consistent whack-a-mole with outbreaks and on-off lockdowns. Despite implementing measures that would not be legal in the United States, the country is now experiencing a surge in cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/south_korea_cases.png&#34; alt=&#34;South Korea&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about New Zealand? Haven&amp;rsquo;t they eradicated the virus? They&amp;rsquo;ve managed to survive 100 days without a single COVID-19 transmission. Sure, New Zealand is a small island with a population of 5 million and a single major airport. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult to suppress transmissions in the long-run; however, the virus eventually resurged without a single transmission from outside the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now confirmed cases have gone from an average of one per day to an average of 10 per day; Auckland is now back in lockdown; and their Prime Minister has delayed their national election [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/new_zealand_cases.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a novel virus, which means that unless there is a vaccine, everyone will be exposed to it eventually. Keeping people locked inside doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop the disease; it only delays it. Unfortunately, keeping people locked inside until the spread slows down, or until vaccine, is a very popular solution to a very unsustainable problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eventually-swedens-strategy-will-by-everyones-strategy&#34;&gt;Eventually Sweden&amp;rsquo;s Strategy Will By Everyone&amp;rsquo;s Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve barely mentioned Sweden in this post. As much of the Western world was shutting down large portions of the economy and limiting the mobility of its citizens throughout March, Sweden opted for a much lighter touch. They&amp;rsquo;ve refused to close down service industries, schools are largely left open, and its borders remained open to the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirmed cases spiked as high as 2,530 in a single day (1,247 per day on average); Sweden reached this milestone in early July. At the same time, fatalities have reached as high as 185, 107 per day on average, a milestone in early May. Both metrics have been on a downward trend since, on some recent days, the country has recorded as few as 3 COVID fatalities. The region is also currently averaging 253 new cases per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/sweden_cases_deaths.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockdowns and closed boarders lack a historical, scientific basis from the Swedish perspective. COVID-19 is in every European country, and so far, none of them have been able to slow down the spread considerably. Regardless, journalists and political analysts have considered Sweden a &amp;ldquo;cautionary tale&amp;rdquo; for the world [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;]. They justify this claim by correctly pointing out that Sweden&amp;rsquo;s population-adjusted death rate is significantly higher compared to its Scandinavian neighbors Finland, Denmark, and Norway [&lt;a href=&#34;#10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Sweden ran into similar problems as many other places had in their attempts to control the virus through the least vulnerable population: failing to protect the elderly. According to most research, upwards of 70% of the COVID death toll in Sweden has been people in elderly care services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the same token, people 65 and older comprise 80% of all COVID deaths in the United States. U.S. Governors such as Andrew Cuomo have been heavily criticized by having the highest nursing home death toll in the U.S., despite instituted one of the strongest and most restrictive lockdowns in the country. Despite reaching Phrase Four of its reopening plan, much of the New York economy is still under lockdown; NYC&amp;rsquo;s mayor Bill DeBlasio is still enforcing strict social distancing requirements (except for protest, apparently).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/COVID-V-Economy/sweden_outperforms.png&#34; alt=&#34;New Zealand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of Sweden&amp;rsquo;s strategy, at least from Sweden&amp;rsquo;s perspective, is that places that have locked down significantly lower immunity levels than Sweden&amp;rsquo;s. As such, these places may need to lock down again if and when the disease returns (it has already returned). Many experts have claimed that COVID-19, like some other respiratory diseases, will only be subject to the effects of herd immunity when anywhere from 60-80% of the population recovers from it. No one knows what level of serology represents what is known as Heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (NIT), but we do know that antibody studies are undercounting the population&amp;rsquo;s immunity [&lt;a href=&#34;#11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;][&lt;a href=&#34;#12&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden&amp;rsquo;s steady decline in deaths and cases may present an advantage very few countries have obtained. Other hands that have managed to clamp down on infections are seeing a daily increase in cases. This suggests that other places around the world may have populations that may be more susceptible to the virus than Sweden. As such, Sweden&amp;rsquo;s economy may be better off in the long run without the on-and-off lockdowns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at Sweden, it may come across as insane that they&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take this approach. However, their approach was the basic science and standard pandemic response prior to 2020 [&lt;a href=&#34;#13&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;]. With that being said, are &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; the insane ones?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, fall is just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.igmchicago.org/surveys/policy-for-the-covid-19-crisis/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IGM Forum | Policy for the COVID-19 Crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2020/national/states-reopening-coronavirus-map/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Washington Post | Where states reopened and cases spiked after U.S. shutdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-europe-slowed-its-coronavirus-cases-from-a-torrent-to-a-trickle-11595240731&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal | How Europe Kept Coronavirus Cases Low Even After Reopening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/08/lockdowns-cant-end-until-covid-19-vaccine-found-study-says&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Guardian | Study: Lockdowns can&amp;rsquo;t end until COVID-19 vaccine is found&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-newzealand/new-cases-end-new-zealands-covid-free-status-auckland-back-in-lockdown-idUSKCN257197&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reuters | New Zealand Ends &amp;lsquo;COVID-Free&amp;rsquo; Status; Ackland Back in Lockdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-53796434&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BBC | Jacinda Ardern Delay Election Over Coronavirus Fears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/07/business/sweden-economy-coronavirus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Times | Sweden Has Become the World&amp;rsquo;s Cautionary Tale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;10&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/07/business/sweden-economy-coronavirus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Our World in Data | Scandinavian COVID-19 Population-Adjusted Death Rate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;11&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heparin-induced_thrombocytopenia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikipedia | Heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (NIT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;12&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.propublica.org/article/what-antibody-studies-can-tell-you-and-more-importantly-what-they-cant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ProPublica | What Antibody Studies Can Tell You — and More Importantly, What They Can’t &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;13&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/sweden-under-fire-for-relaxed-coronavirus-approach-heres-the-science-behind-it-134926&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Conversation | Sweden under fire for ‘relaxed’ coronavirus approach – here’s the science behind it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
