<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New York | KidQuant</title>
    <link>https://kidquant.com/tag/new-york/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kidquant.com/tag/new-york/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>New York</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://kidquant.com/media/icon_huf195f9a67bfe19c82d5f0ba6a67922fa_2030_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>New York</title>
      <link>https://kidquant.com/tag/new-york/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York State of Decline</title>
      <link>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kidquant.com/post/2020-09-12-ny-state-of-decline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how New York became America&amp;rsquo;s financial center? It&amp;rsquo;s not like the New York Stock Exchange is the only securities market in the country. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s the NASDAQ (another in New York), but there is one in Miami, Chicago, and Philidelphia. In fact, Philadelphia initially obtained financial supremacy in the country with the establishment of the Bank of Pennsylvania in 1780.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I learned during my Finance undergraduate studies, it all amounts to pure luck why Philadephia isn&amp;rsquo;t America&amp;rsquo;s financial center. The main reason why economic supremacy shifted from Philly was NYC&amp;rsquo;s geographical advantage with the Erie Canal construction. The Erie Canal connected to the Hudson River to the Great Lakes and the fastest-growing places in the Appalachian Mountains. The canal helped solidify New York&amp;rsquo;s position as America&amp;rsquo;s center for commercial trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point of this history lesson: nothing lasts forever. If a country, region, state, or area loses its comparative advantage, it may also lose its overall economic advantage. Enter James Altucher, author of the &lt;em&gt;NYC is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/em&gt; article [&lt;a href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. He wrote a scathing rebuke of the current situation involving New York City, arguing, although the city has been through a lot, this time is different. James obviously addressed all of the crucial points, which are undeniably true. Why else would high profile individuals such as Jerry Seinfield, Mark Cuban, and Bill De&amp;rsquo;Blasio respond to an article on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say whether I agree with the points raised in the article; there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot that I can add to strengthen the &amp;ldquo;New York is Dead&amp;rdquo; argument. We can debate what it would mean for an entire city to be &amp;ldquo;dead,&amp;rdquo; whether it&amp;rsquo;s fewer people choosing to travel to NYC or high-net-worth individuals and established industries choosing to relocate to other areas. What I can say is that the threats to New York&amp;rsquo;s financial position are &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, James outlines that many people in March/April relocated when the Pandemic situation in NYC worsened; the second wave of people left when crime was spiraling out of control. Some may suggest that the stores of New Yorkers fleeing the city in droves may be greatly exaggerated [&lt;a href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that the COVID pandemic merely exacerbated what many New Yorkers have been feeling all along: &amp;ldquo;I gotta get out of here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows anything about living in New York understands how unfeasible it is to maintain a decent standard of living unless you&amp;rsquo;re very poor or wealthy [&lt;a href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_pop_change.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Population Change&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following map shows the population change of New York counties within the last 9 years. The plot measures cumulative growth since April 2010; each county is shaded in a different color. The closer the shade is to blue, the larger the population growth within the last 9 years (and vice versa). As we can see, change in the NY population has been on a steady decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the five boroughs, except Richmond County (Staten Island), are the only counties with experienced population growth within the same period, albeit very modest. Regardless, Census Bureau data suggest that NYC has been bleeding residents as early as 2016 [&lt;a href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t clear whether COVID and crime are the final straw for many life-long New Yorkers. Instead, the current situation has allowed people to imagine the possibility of becoming life-long somewhere-elsers. As James pointed out, people are willing to tolerate the higher taxes and cost of living because of business/employment opportunities and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kidquant.com/post/images/NY-State-Of-Decline/ny_ue_rate.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Unemployment Rate&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is a plot of the same region, except this measures the August Unemployment by county. The vast majority of areas in New York have an unemployment rate similar to the national average of 8.4 percent. In stark contrast, the five boroughs (and the surrounding areas) have unemployment rates significantly above the national average, ranging from 12 percent to as high as 20 percent. This unemployment level is consistent with the severe COVID restrictions still imposed on many industries in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind, NYC and New York as a whole have not experienced a second wave in the same way other cities across the globe have. Governor Cuomo once suggested that people were &amp;ldquo;fleeing other states because it&amp;rsquo;s a safe state.&amp;rdquo; [&lt;a href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] While there is nothing to indicate that people have weighed the opportunity cost of looking for work as opposed to catching COVID,. Instead, people have decided that it&amp;rsquo;s too expensive to live in NYC for all of the city&amp;rsquo;s headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be realistic; changes in mortgage rates and what people are looking for in a home provide an incentive for people who were already considering moving. The largest incentive for people living in the city (doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter which city) is the cost [&lt;a href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]. In addition, ~80 percent of NYC employees live in the five boroughs; with NYC-based firms offering more flexible work-from-home policies, that number is likely to decline [&lt;a href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]. Lastly, the COVID Pandemic prevents NYC residents from fully enjoying local amenities, which lowers the incentive to live here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if there is no incentive to live here, there is also no incentive to conduct business here. Manhattan Borough President Gale Brewer counted 335 street-level vacancies along Broadway (a ~80 increase from three years ago), a major shopping area/tourist attraction in NYC [&lt;a href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;]. Other industries are just as amenable to the effects of the pandemic as well. Still, the one affected industry that has the power to effectively reshape NYC is, of course, the &lt;strong&gt;Financial sector&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, New Yorkers (at least, NYC-based finance employees) debated where the next financial hotspot would be, and for a long time, that hotspot appeared to be Hudson Yards. Today, as work-from-home policies have reduced the need for employees in office environments, financial firms are considering reducing its physical presence by at least 20%, according to a study released by the Partnership for New York City [&lt;a href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same study has also pointed out that 1 in four office employers intend to reduce their footprint by at least a fifth, and about 16 percent expect to move jobs out of the city. Companies also expect only 10 percent of their employees to return to the office by the end of summer and just 40 percent by the year-end. The lack of mobility is expected to shrink economic activity by 13 percent this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a personal anecdote, I was expected to return back to the office in mid-September; however, my firm has left work-from-home optional for many employees. From what I here, the office is mostly empty, which should surprise no one. As long as resturants and businesses remain closed, as long as the number of businesses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/nyc-dead-forever-heres-why-james-altucher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James Altucher | NYC Is Dead Forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://nypost.com/2020/08/11/new-yorkers-flee-nyc-in-droves/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Post | New Yorkers Keep Moving To The Suburbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://money.cnn.com/calculator/pf/cost-of-living/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CNBC Money | Cost of Living City Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/fredgraph.png?g=w7H1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FRED | Resident Population in NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thehill/status/1285337437867212802?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1285337437867212802%7Ctwgr%5Eshare_0&amp;amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fdw-site-staging.dailywire.com%2Fnews%2Fandrew-cuomo-claims-people-are-now-fleeing-to-new-york-because-its-safe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hill | New York State Governor Andrew Cuomo Press Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;6&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redfin.com/blog/wfh-leaving-new-york-san-francisco/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RedFin | Post-Pandemic Migration from Expensive Cities Likely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;7&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www1.nyc.gov/assets/planning/download/pdf/planning-level/housing-economy/nyc-ins-and-out-of-commuting.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NYC Planning Department | The Ins and Outs of NYC Commuting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;8&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/business-vacancies-rise-on-new-york-citys-broadway-11599652800#:~:text=Coronavirus%20pandemic%20strains%20companies%20along,street-level%20vacancies%20along%20Broadway.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal | Business Vacanies Rise on New York City&amp;rsquo;s Broadway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a name=&#34;9&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;] &lt;a href=&#34;https://pfnyc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/actionandcollaboration.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Partnership for New York City | A Call for Action and Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
